<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Server on m365 blog</title>
    <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/project-server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project Server on m365 blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 20:59:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/project-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add SSRS report to Project Detail Page Project Server</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/add-ssrs-report-to-project-detail-page-project-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 20:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/add-ssrs-report-to-project-detail-page-project-server/</guid>
      <description>Often clients want to be able to drill down to SSRS reports with the project pre selected when they are viewing project information from project detail pages. This post describes how to embed SSRS report in a project detail page.
Add SSRS Report to Project Detail Page in Project Server 1. Navigate to a PDP (Project Detail Page) , e.g. Schedule PDP. 2. Edit Page 3. Click “Add a Web Part”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a TimeLine View for Milestones and Project Duration using Matrix in SSRS</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-a-timeline-view-for-milestones-in-ssrs-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-a-timeline-view-for-milestones-in-ssrs-comments/</guid>
      <description>Julia - Jul 4, 2017
Is it possible to insert a Linebreak after each Milestone? So if you have a bunch of Milestones that you can read it more easily.
It&amp;rsquo;s quit easy to add a Linebreak in Tooltipp. Just edited the Statement as below: ,(STUFF( ( SELECT &amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo; + convert(nvarchar(3), day(TaskFinishDate)) + &amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo; + + convert(char(3), TaskFinishDate , 0) + &amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo; + + convert(nvarchar(6), year(TaskFinishDate)) + &amp;rsquo; - &amp;rsquo; + T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a TimeLine View for Milestones and Project Duration using Matrix in SSRS</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-a-timeline-view-for-milestones-in-ssrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-a-timeline-view-for-milestones-in-ssrs/</guid>
      <description>A range chart in SSRS can be used to produce a Gantt chart.of project. Below is a link to a great post that explains how to do it. http://pnarayanaswamy.blogspot.co.uk/2010/09/range-bar-chart-gantt-chart-using-ssrs.html Unfortunately I have found the following limitations
The width and height of the range chart does not grow dynamically when run. If too much data is displayed, the chart is unreadable To counteract the above limitations, I have used the matrix control which can grow dynamically in terms of width and height to fit the data which remains readable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building SSRS using Report Builder for Project Server On Premises</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/building-ssrs-using-report-builder-for-project-server-on-premises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/building-ssrs-using-report-builder-for-project-server-on-premises/</guid>
      <description>1. Article Purpose I have worked with SSRS for nearly five years now. It is an efficient tool to display data from Project Server Reporting database. This article provides a step to step guide how to create reports using Report Builder from Project Server 2010 /2013 (On Premises) environment.
2. Report Builder Report Builder is a report authoring tool that helps to design, test, print and manage reports. Different type of reports can be created using a combination of tables, matrices, lists, and charts depending on reporting needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Function to return ISO Week and ISO Year Project Server</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sql-function-to-return-iso-week-and-iso-year-project-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 14:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sql-function-to-return-iso-week-and-iso-year-project-server/</guid>
      <description>The table MSP_TimeByDay in the reporting database for on premise Project Server stores date information in day, week, year, quarter , etc.. Unfortunately the columns TimeWeekOfTheYear and TimeYear does not store ISO week and year. The following function returns the ISO week and ISO Year of the date passed. CREATE FUNCTION [dbo].[FN_UTILITY_ConvertToWeekDate] ( @Date datetime ) RETURNS nvarchar(255) AS BEGIN DECLARE @output nvarchar(255) SET @output = (SELECT RIGHT(&#39;00&#39; + CAST(Q.ISOweek AS NVARCHAR(2)), 2) + &#39;-&#39; + CAST(CASE WHEN MONTH(@Date) = 1 AND Q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange ActiveSync</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/exchange-activesync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 15:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/exchange-activesync/</guid>
      <description>Exchange ActiveSync devices can be configures to allow users to work in remote locations with high-latency or low-bandwidth networks. It allows users to access and reply to email messages and access calendars even when they are offline. Below is a link to Exchange ActiveSync http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa998357(v=exchg.150).aspx</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
