<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reagent on m365 blog</title>
    <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/reagent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reagent on m365 blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 13:31:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/reagent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Input of type date to generate a date picker using Reagent in ClojureScript</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/input-of-type-date-to-generate-a-date-picker-using-reagent-in-clojurescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/input-of-type-date-to-generate-a-date-picker-using-reagent-in-clojurescript/</guid>
      <description>I needed a date picker to use in ClojureScript application to enter date of birth. I came across the pikaday which I tried to use but the date range was limited and could not find a solution to not limit the date range. The native HTML input control of type date can be generated in Reagent as follows [:p &amp;quot;Enter Date Of Birth&amp;quot;] ;;using input control of type date to allow a date to be picked [:input {:type &amp;quot;date&amp;quot; :on-change (fn [e] (swap!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript - Power of Clojure to the web</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/clojurescript-power-of-clojure-to-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/clojurescript-power-of-clojure-to-the-web/</guid>
      <description>ClojureScript is a compiler for Clojure that targets JavaScript. It is designed to emit JavaScript code which is compatible with the advanced compilation mode of the Google Closure optimizing compiler. Why ClojureScript?
Allows to use functional programming. Uses Immutable data structures. (Immutable.js library is available to enable use of immutable data structures with JavaScript. Watch Christian Johansen&amp;rsquo;s talk on Immutable JavaScript) Uses Google Closure Compiler : advanced code compiling with dead code elimination core.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
