<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Functional Programming on m365 blog</title>
    <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/functional-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Functional Programming on m365 blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 07:31:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/functional-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>London ClojureBridge Event as Teaching Assistant</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/london-clojurebridge-event-as-teaching-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 07:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/london-clojurebridge-event-as-teaching-assistant/</guid>
      <description>Clojurebridge experience as teaching assistant I have been learning Clojure/ClojureScript over the last three months in my spare time. I felt lucky to be asked to volunteer to be a teaching assistant for the ClojureBridge event held at USwitch on the 19th and 20th Feb 2016. I was feeling apprehensive initially due to my limited exposure to a functional programming language and most of the teachers and teaching assistants were either working full time with Clojure or had several years of playing with Clojure and were using a Mac while I have used Windows laptop to play with Clojure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript - Power of Clojure to the web</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/clojurescript-power-of-clojure-to-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/clojurescript-power-of-clojure-to-the-web/</guid>
      <description>ClojureScript is a compiler for Clojure that targets JavaScript. It is designed to emit JavaScript code which is compatible with the advanced compilation mode of the Google Closure optimizing compiler. Why ClojureScript?
Allows to use functional programming. Uses Immutable data structures. (Immutable.js library is available to enable use of immutable data structures with JavaScript. Watch Christian Johansen&amp;rsquo;s talk on Immutable JavaScript) Uses Google Closure Compiler : advanced code compiling with dead code elimination core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure Destructuring</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/clojure-destructuring-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 09:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/clojure-destructuring-comments/</guid>
      <description>Links &amp;amp; Reads from 2015 Week 50 – Martin&#39;s Weekly Curations - Feb 1, 2016
[…] Clojure Destructuring […]
Utterly indited articles , thankyou for entropy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure Destructuring</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/clojure-destructuring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 09:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/clojure-destructuring/</guid>
      <description>Destructuring allows to extract values from datastructures and bind them to symbols without explicitly looping/traversing the datastructure. It allows concise and simple coding.
Sequential Destructuring Provides vector of symbols to bind by position. Syntax: [symbol another-symbol] [&amp;ldquo;value&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;another-value&amp;rdquo;] (def listNumbers[7 8 9 10 11]) ;;Bind a, b, c to first 3 values in stuff (let [[a b c] listNumbers] (list (+ a b) (+ b c))) Result: (15,17) It binds to nil if there&amp;rsquo;s no data, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting with Clojure: Factorial function</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/starting-with-clojure-environment-set-up-in-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 23:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/starting-with-clojure-environment-set-up-in-windows/</guid>
      <description>My background is mainly C# with some JavaScript. I have heard a lot about functional programming languages like Clojure, F# and Scala. I decided to start learning Clojure. My first reaction after seeing a Clojure code was the syntax and layout which was unreadable to me. Clojure is a member of the Lisp family of languages. The use of parentheses is prominent. Below is some code that calculates factorial of a number in Clojure (defn fac &amp;quot;Returns factorial of n&amp;quot; [n] (if (= n 1) 1 (* n (fac (- n 1))))) Parentheses are used to structure lists and lists are building blocks of code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
