<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SSRS on m365 blog</title>
    <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/ssrs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SSRS on m365 blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 17:35:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/ssrs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CRM Dynamics 2015 &#34;Error Uploading Report&#34; caused by using Visual Studio 2015</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/crm-dynamics-2015-error-uploading-report-caused-by-using-visual-studio-2015-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 17:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/crm-dynamics-2015-error-uploading-report-caused-by-using-visual-studio-2015-comments/</guid>
      <description>sherry - Dec 1, 2017
this is a good solution, however i&amp;rsquo;ll add more to it. If you want to find out exactly what the error is. Logon to machine which has sql server instance for the CRM. Check event viewer and see the errors for MSCRMReporting and it will tell you what the error is. In this case it is the version incompatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRM Dynamics 2015 &#34;Error Uploading Report&#34; caused by using Visual Studio 2015</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/crm-dynamics-2015-error-uploading-report-caused-by-using-visual-studio-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 17:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/crm-dynamics-2015-error-uploading-report-caused-by-using-visual-studio-2015/</guid>
      <description>When I was trying to upload a SSRS report to replace an existing report to CRM Dynamics 2015 solution, I got the error Error Uploading Report An error occurred while trying to add the report to Microsoft Dynamics CRM. The error message does not say much. I decided to use Visual Studio 2015 to edit the CRM report which has caused the issue. I compared the code behind of the previous report and new report and found that there are new XML elements in the report generated by visual studio 2015 (SQL Server Data Tools for Visual Studio 2015).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drilling Down to a Report in a new tab SSRS Integrated Mode</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/drilling-down-to-a-report-in-a-new-tab-ssrs-integrated-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 21:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/drilling-down-to-a-report-in-a-new-tab-ssrs-integrated-mode/</guid>
      <description>There are two ways to navigate to another SSRS from a main Report
Action “Go to Report” Right-click on a TextBox, select Text Box Properties, select Action tab and select option “Go to report”. Click on “Browse” and select the SSRS Report from the report library. If the selected SSRS Report has parameters, click on “Add” to add parameter. From the “Name” dropdown select the parameter name and from the “Value” dropdown select the value to pass to the parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add SSRS report to Project Detail Page Project Server</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/add-ssrs-report-to-project-detail-page-project-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 20:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/add-ssrs-report-to-project-detail-page-project-server/</guid>
      <description>Often clients want to be able to drill down to SSRS reports with the project pre selected when they are viewing project information from project detail pages. This post describes how to embed SSRS report in a project detail page.
Add SSRS Report to Project Detail Page in Project Server 1. Navigate to a PDP (Project Detail Page) , e.g. Schedule PDP. 2. Edit Page 3. Click “Add a Web Part”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS SharePoint Integrated Mode - Cells grow vertically to fit content</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode-cells-grow-vertically-to-fit-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 17:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode-cells-grow-vertically-to-fit-content/</guid>
      <description>I have come across this issue several times that even the &amp;ldquo;Can Grow&amp;rdquo; property of the cell is set to false, the cell grows vertically to fit contents forcing the same row to stretch to the height of the cell distorting the rendering of the report on the browser though it might display correctly in Report Builder or SQL data tools in Visual Studio. Can Grow is set to False from the cell property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restricting SSRS Report to show only projects users are allowed to see in Project Server 2010/2013 On Premises</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/restricting-ssrs-report-to-show-only-projects-users-are-allowed-to-see-in-project-server-20102013-on-premises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 19:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/restricting-ssrs-report-to-show-only-projects-users-are-allowed-to-see-in-project-server-20102013-on-premises/</guid>
      <description>To restrict the projects users can see from SSRS, there are several options
1. Use the published database. However Microsoft does not recommend querying directly published database. This approach can be used at your own risk. CREATE FUNCTION [dbo].[PWA_FN_UTILITY_GetProjectsUserCanViewProjectDetails] ( @WRES_NT_ACCOUNT nvarchar(255) ) RETURNS @OUTPUT TABLE ( ProjectUID uniqueidentifier ) AS BEGIN DECLARE @RES_UID uniqueidentifier -- get the user account from the published database, also available in reporting database -- but in reporting database no indication if user is just a resource or an actual user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a TimeLine View for Milestones and Project Duration using Matrix in SSRS</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-a-timeline-view-for-milestones-in-ssrs-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-a-timeline-view-for-milestones-in-ssrs-comments/</guid>
      <description>Julia - Jul 4, 2017
Is it possible to insert a Linebreak after each Milestone? So if you have a bunch of Milestones that you can read it more easily.
It&amp;rsquo;s quit easy to add a Linebreak in Tooltipp. Just edited the Statement as below: ,(STUFF( ( SELECT &amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo; + convert(nvarchar(3), day(TaskFinishDate)) + &amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo; + + convert(char(3), TaskFinishDate , 0) + &amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo; + + convert(nvarchar(6), year(TaskFinishDate)) + &amp;rsquo; - &amp;rsquo; + T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a TimeLine View for Milestones and Project Duration using Matrix in SSRS</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-a-timeline-view-for-milestones-in-ssrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-a-timeline-view-for-milestones-in-ssrs/</guid>
      <description>A range chart in SSRS can be used to produce a Gantt chart.of project. Below is a link to a great post that explains how to do it. http://pnarayanaswamy.blogspot.co.uk/2010/09/range-bar-chart-gantt-chart-using-ssrs.html Unfortunately I have found the following limitations
The width and height of the range chart does not grow dynamically when run. If too much data is displayed, the chart is unreadable To counteract the above limitations, I have used the matrix control which can grow dynamically in terms of width and height to fit the data which remains readable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building SSRS using Report Builder for Project Server On Premises</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/building-ssrs-using-report-builder-for-project-server-on-premises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/building-ssrs-using-report-builder-for-project-server-on-premises/</guid>
      <description>1. Article Purpose I have worked with SSRS for nearly five years now. It is an efficient tool to display data from Project Server Reporting database. This article provides a step to step guide how to create reports using Report Builder from Project Server 2010 /2013 (On Premises) environment.
2. Report Builder Report Builder is a report authoring tool that helps to design, test, print and manage reports. Different type of reports can be created using a combination of tables, matrices, lists, and charts depending on reporting needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS Subscription SharePoint Integrated Mode</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-subscription-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 16:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-subscription-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</guid>
      <description>Subscription option is available on the SSRS report item to allow the run the report automatically. The user need to be logged in as site administrator to create subscription. Follow the steps below
Create a document library (named for example “Extracts” to store the report extracts. Click on “Manage Subscriptions” from the drop down options available against the SSRS report item. Click on “Add Subscription”. Update the fields Delivery Extension = SharePoint Document Library Document Library = The document library created in first step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Date Parameterer to en-GB SSRS 2012 SharePoint Integrated mode</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/changing-date-parameterer-to-en-gb-ssrs-2012-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 16:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/changing-date-parameterer-to-en-gb-ssrs-2012-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</guid>
      <description>I have seen the issues several times where date/time parameters used to filter date in SSRS reports are switched to en-US despite the language of the reports is set to en-GB. If dates like 24/12/2015 or 15/12/2015 are picked , the report fails to load due to invalid date format. I came across the article that describes a fix. http://www.tachytelic.net/2013/01/changing-the-format-of-date-parameters-on-a-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-report-that-is-sharepoint-integrated/ Hard code the UICulture value in RSViewerPage.aspx, found in C:\Program Files\Common Files\Microsoft Shared\Web Server Extensions\15\TEMPLATE\LAYOUTS\ReportServer The modified code will look like: &amp;lt;%@ Page language=&amp;ldquo;C#&amp;rdquo; Codebehind=&amp;ldquo;RSViewerPage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS Format Currency in thousands with suffix K</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-format-currency-in-thousands-with-suffix-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 17:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-format-currency-in-thousands-with-suffix-k/</guid>
      <description>Currency values can be displayed in thousands with k suffix using the format &amp;lsquo;£&amp;rsquo;#,0,&amp;lsquo;k&amp;rsquo;;(&amp;lsquo;£&amp;rsquo;#,0,&amp;lsquo;k&amp;rsquo;) Edit the Format property of the textbox with &amp;lsquo;£&amp;rsquo;#,0,&amp;lsquo;k&amp;rsquo;;(&amp;lsquo;£&amp;rsquo;#,0,&amp;lsquo;k&amp;rsquo;) Running the report, all values will be displayed in thousands with K suffix and currency symbol as prefix. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Get Financial Year (April to March)</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sql-get-financial-year-april-to-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 17:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sql-get-financial-year-april-to-march/</guid>
      <description>The following query will return the financial year starting April to March YEAR(DATEADD(Month,-((DATEPART(Month,StartDate)+8) %12),StartDate)) SELECT YEAR(DATEADD(Month,-((DATEPART(Month,&amp;lsquo;2014-03-31&amp;rsquo;)+8) %12),&amp;lsquo;2014-03-31&amp;rsquo;)) SELECT YEAR(DATEADD(Month,-((DATEPART(Month,&amp;lsquo;2014-04-01&amp;rsquo;)+8) %12),&amp;lsquo;2014-04-01&amp;rsquo;)) SELECT YEAR(DATEADD(Month,-((DATEPART(Month,&amp;lsquo;2014-12-31&amp;rsquo;)+8) %12),&amp;lsquo;2014-12-31&amp;rsquo;)) SELECT YEAR(DATEADD(Month,-((DATEPART(Month,&amp;lsquo;2015-03-31&amp;rsquo;)+8) %12),&amp;lsquo;2015-03-31&amp;rsquo;)) SELECT YEAR(DATEADD(Month,-((DATEPART(Month,&amp;lsquo;2015-04-01&amp;rsquo;)+8) %12),&amp;lsquo;2015-04-01&amp;rsquo;)) The results are </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing Date Parameter To SubReport SSRS SharePoint Integrated Mode</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/passing-date-parameter-to-subreport-ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 18:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/passing-date-parameter-to-subreport-ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</guid>
      <description>When SSRS is rendered in SharePoint Integrated Mode if there is a drop down parameter of type DateTime and it is passed to a parameter of DateTime in the SubReport, the subreport fails to load when rendering in browser though it loads correctly from reportbuilder. Again much pain, I decided to convert the date parameters into Text as the parameters were drop down displaying in dd/MM/yyyy format. The SQL query to populate the parameter SELECT CONVERT(nvarchar(10),Min(TimeByDay),103) DisplayDate ,Convert(date,Min(TimeByDay)) StartTime ,CONVERT(VARCHAR(10), Min(TimeByDay), 112) FormatStartTime FROM [dbo].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Function to return ISO Week and ISO Year Project Server</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sql-function-to-return-iso-week-and-iso-year-project-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 14:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sql-function-to-return-iso-week-and-iso-year-project-server/</guid>
      <description>The table MSP_TimeByDay in the reporting database for on premise Project Server stores date information in day, week, year, quarter , etc.. Unfortunately the columns TimeWeekOfTheYear and TimeYear does not store ISO week and year. The following function returns the ISO week and ISO Year of the date passed. CREATE FUNCTION [dbo].[FN_UTILITY_ConvertToWeekDate] ( @Date datetime ) RETURNS nvarchar(255) AS BEGIN DECLARE @output nvarchar(255) SET @output = (SELECT RIGHT(&#39;00&#39; + CAST(Q.ISOweek AS NVARCHAR(2)), 2) + &#39;-&#39; + CAST(CASE WHEN MONTH(@Date) = 1 AND Q.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS Export to PDF results in sentence to be concatenated into one long word</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-export-to-pdf-results-in-sentence-to-be-concatenated-into-one-long-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 14:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-export-to-pdf-results-in-sentence-to-be-concatenated-into-one-long-word/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes invalid ASCII code invisible to naked eye are stored in the SQL database. If the value with the invalid ASCII is displayed in a SSRS report and exported to PDF, the set of words become concatenated into one word Example &amp;ldquo;The director of the company has given approval&amp;rdquo; displayed in a textbox in SSRS become &amp;ldquo;Thedirectorofthecompanyhasgivenapproval&amp;rdquo; in PDF. The first character of the text value was ASCII code 63. Unfortunately there are other characters that are mapped to 63.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get week number based on start date of financial year - April</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/get-week-number-based-on-start-date-of-financial-year-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 12:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/get-week-number-based-on-start-date-of-financial-year-april/</guid>
      <description>Most organisations start their financial year in April in UK. The requirement is to set first week in April to 1. I have found the script from blog which creates a function which fulfills the objective above. See more at: http://www.sqlteam.com/article/returning-a-week-number-for-any-given-date-and-starting-fiscal-month#sthash.vegLomU6.dpuf CREATE FUNCTION GetFiscalWeek (@startMonth varchar(2), @myDate datetime) RETURNS INT AS BEGIN declare @firstWeek datetime declare @weekNum int declare @year int set @year = datepart(year, @myDate)+1 --Get 4th day of month of next year, this will always be in week 1 set @firstWeek = convert(datetime, str(@year)+@startMonth+&#39;04&#39;, 102) --Retreat to beginning of week set @firstWeek = dateadd(day, (1-datepart(dw, @firstWeek)), @firstWeek) WHILE @myDate &amp;lt; @firstWeek --Repeat the above steps but for previous year BEGIN set @year = @year - 1 set @firstWeek = convert(datetime, str(@year)+@startMonth+&#39;04&#39;, 102) set @firstWeek = dateadd(day, (1-datepart(dw, @firstWeek)), @firstWeek) END SET @weekNum = (@year*100)+((datediff(day, @firstweek, @myDate)/7)+1) RETURN @weekNum END Examples of using the function Use SET DATEFIRST 1 to set the first day of the week to be Monday SET DATEFIRST 1 Select [dbo].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stripping HTML tags from SSRS text fields</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/stripping-html-tags-from-ssrs-text-fields-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 09:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/stripping-html-tags-from-ssrs-text-fields-comments/</guid>
      <description>TimK - Jun 4, 2017
Appreciate the code. One question; Why is this required? Dim objRegExp AS NEW System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex( “”) and RETURN objRegExp.Replace(sInput, “”) Wouldn’t a simple return of sInput suffice? What am I missing here? Been racking my brain for hours. Thanks!
Hi TimK The HTML text I had to work with had encoded characters , for example &amp;ldquo;&amp;amp;&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;&amp;amp;&amp;rdquo;. The regex expression will remove all HTML tags but for my requirements, I wanted to preserve line breaks () , so I am handling these tags individually to be replaced with line feed (chr(10)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stripping HTML tags from SSRS text fields</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/stripping-html-tags-from-ssrs-text-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 09:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/stripping-html-tags-from-ssrs-text-fields/</guid>
      <description>I have worked extensively with SSRS. One of the common requirements is to strip HTML from text values displayed in reports and apply standard formatting to the text. HTML have many encoded characters which end users don&amp;rsquo;t want to see. The function below replaces encoded characters to the correct string http://www.w3schools.com/tags/ref_urlencode.asp The requirement was to add a carriage return whenever a &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; is found. Because in some text the &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; was &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;, additional code has been added to cater for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges using SSRS SharePoint Integrated Mode in Chrome when kerberos is enabled</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/challenges-using-ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode-in-chrome-when-kerberos-is-enabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 16:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/challenges-using-ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode-in-chrome-when-kerberos-is-enabled/</guid>
      <description>On one client&amp;rsquo;s environment SSRS reports on Dev, Test and Live SharePoint 2013 Integrated mode with kerberos used for authentication will not load if they are opened in Chrome. Only the loading wheel can be seen. If the browser&amp;rsquo;s developer tool is opened, the same requests in being sent non stopping. This is happening when the SSRS report is opened either from report library or through a SSRS web part on a page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange ActiveSync</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/exchange-activesync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 15:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/exchange-activesync/</guid>
      <description>Exchange ActiveSync devices can be configures to allow users to work in remote locations with high-latency or low-bandwidth networks. It allows users to access and reply to email messages and access calendars even when they are offline. Below is a link to Exchange ActiveSync http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa998357(v=exchg.150).aspx</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
