<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PnP Migration Site Columns Content Types SharePoint 2013 SharePoint Online on Reshmee Auckloo</title><link>https://reshmee.netlify.app/tags/pnp-migration-site-columns-content-types-sharepoint-2013-sharepoint-online/</link><description>Recent content in PnP Migration Site Columns Content Types SharePoint 2013 SharePoint Online on Reshmee Auckloo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 11:52:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reshmee.netlify.app/tags/pnp-migration-site-columns-content-types-sharepoint-2013-sharepoint-online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Import/Export Columns and Content Types using PnP PowerShell</title><link>https://reshmee.netlify.app/posts/importexport-columns-and-content-types-sharepointpnp2016powershell-powershell-comments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 11:52:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reshmee.netlify.app/posts/importexport-columns-and-content-types-sharepointpnp2016powershell-powershell-comments/</guid><description>reshmee011 - Oct 4, 2017
I will update the scripts at some point. Thanks for the comment.
The Imported TaxonomyFields seems not working, because of missing the second Taxonomy-Note-Field. I always get &amp;ldquo;The SPListItem being updated was not retrieved with all taxonomy fields&amp;rdquo; in Edit-Form of the imported Managed Metadata Columns. I have observed this. http://blog.bugrapostaci.com/2015/07/03/the-splistitem-being-updated-was-not-retrieved-with-all-taxonomy-fields/
Actually you must use the new PnP-PowerShell-Namespace in the PowerShell-Commands. Example: Connect-PnPOnline instead of Connect-SPOnline and so on&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Import/Export Columns and Content Types using PnP PowerShell</title><link>https://reshmee.netlify.app/posts/importexport-columns-and-content-types-sharepointpnp2016powershell-powershell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 11:52:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://reshmee.netlify.app/posts/importexport-columns-and-content-types-sharepointpnp2016powershell-powershell/</guid><description>It is useful to migrate Site Columns and Content Types from one Site Collection to another under the following scenarios maintaining the original GUIDS.
SharePoint On Premise environment to SharePoint Online Within SharePoint Online, migrate to another tenant If Content Hub Feature is not used, migrate the contents to another site collection Keep a list for governance/change tracking purpose, i.e. checking in TFS This article covers export/import of site columns and content types using SharePointPnP2016PowerShell commands which needs to be installed to be able to use the relevant commands.</description></item></channel></rss>