<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SharePoint 2013 on m365 blog</title>
    <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/sharepoint-2013/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SharePoint 2013 on m365 blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 13:59:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/sharepoint-2013/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unable to update User Profile Property due to Policy Settings set to Disabled</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/unable-to-update-user-profile-property-due-to-policy-settings-set-to-disabled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 13:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/unable-to-update-user-profile-property-due-to-policy-settings-set-to-disabled/</guid>
      <description>The web service userprofileservice /_vti_bin/userprofileservice.asmx has to be used to update user profile properties for other users in SharePoint 2013 and SharePoint Online. Even though the HTTP status code response returned was 200 which means successful, the user profile property was blank when the user properties was queried using the REST api method sp.userprofiles.peoplemanager/getpropertiesfor. /_api/sp.userprofiles.peoplemanager/getpropertiesfor(@v)?@v=&amp;lsquo;i%3A0%23.f%7Cmembership%7CfirstName.LastName%40arteliauk.onmicrosoft.com&amp;rsquo; The user profile property updated was PictureUrl , however it was showing as null&amp;lt;d:PictureUrl m:null=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;After spending a couple of hours trying to figure out why the use profile property was not showing, I decided to review the user profiles properties for Picture property and how it is different from the other user profile properties, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to change Content Type of document in Library</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/unable-to-change-content-type-of-document-in-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 12:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/unable-to-change-content-type-of-document-in-library/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to remove a content type from a document library which was associated with multiple content types. As a first action, I identified all documents tagged with the content type to be removed and tried to update them with another content type. However some documents were still showing the old content type despite saving it with the new content type by updating the [Content Type] field. I tried removing the document and adding the document back to the document library, unfortunately it was still referencing the old content type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Dev/Test SharePoint 2013 environment in Azure</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-devtest-sharepoint-2013-environment-in-azure-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 11:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-devtest-sharepoint-2013-environment-in-azure-comments/</guid>
      <description>Create Dev/Test SharePoint 2013 environment in Azure — reshmeeauckloo – SutoCom Solutions - Dec 2, 2016
[…] via Create Dev/Test SharePoint 2013 environment in Azure — reshmeeauckloo […]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Dev/Test SharePoint 2013 environment in Azure</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-devtest-sharepoint-2013-environment-in-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 11:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-devtest-sharepoint-2013-environment-in-azure/</guid>
      <description>Azure has a trial image to build either SharePoint 2013 HA farm or SharePoint 2013 Non-HA farm.
When trying to create SharePoint 2013 Non-HA farm, I was stuck at step &amp;ldquo;Choose storage account type&amp;rdquo; with the message &amp;ldquo;Loading pricing&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;.
Following SharePoint Server 2016 dev/test environment in Azure, I managed to created a SharePoint 2013 environment in Azure running PowerShell commands.
There are three major phases to setting up this dev/test environment:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PnP PowerShell to export and import Taxonomy</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/using-pnp-powershell-to-export-and-import-taxonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/using-pnp-powershell-to-export-and-import-taxonomy/</guid>
      <description>PnP provides export taxonomy cmdlet which allows to export all term groups, term sets, terms and child terms to a file with one line of codeConnect-SPOnline -Url &amp;lt;siteurl&amp;gt; -CurrentCredentials Export-SPOTaxonomy -IncludeID -Path &amp;quot;C:\\temp\\Metadata\\terms.txt&amp;quot;PnP also provides an equivalent import taxonomy cmdlet to import all term groups, term sets, terms and child terms from a file with one line of codeConnect-SPOnline -Url &amp;lt;siteurl&amp;gt; -CurrentCredentials Import-SPOTaxonomy -Path &amp;quot;C:\\temp\\Metadata\\terms.txt&amp;quot;However if IncludeId switch parameter is used with the export, the import would fail if the October 2016 PnP PowerShell release is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Lists Libraries from Schema as XML using CSOM</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-lists-libraries-from-schema-as-xml-using-csom-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 09:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-lists-libraries-from-schema-as-xml-using-csom-comments/</guid>
      <description>Export Lists Schema to XML using CSOM and PnP | reshmeeauckloo - Oct 6, 2016
[…] To create lists/libraries using the XML config file, refer to post Create Lists Libraries from Schema as XML using CSOM […]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Lists Libraries from Schema as XML using CSOM</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-lists-libraries-from-schema-as-xml-using-csom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 09:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-lists-libraries-from-schema-as-xml-using-csom/</guid>
      <description>Following on my article Export List Schema XML to a configuration file, I went on to create lists and libraries with same metadata on a new SharePoint environment. Although CSOM allows to create a list by update the property SchemaXML using CSOM iterating through the list schema in the config file. However I kept getting &amp;ldquo;Invalid list template&amp;rdquo;. The exported list&amp;rsquo;s Schema XML needs to be modified to remove unnecessary tags so as it can be used to update property SchemaXML as per article &amp;ldquo;How to create List and libraries with CustomSchemaXml property using SchemaXml with CSOM in SharePoint online2010?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export Lists Schema to XML using CSOM and PnP</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/export-lists-schema-to-xml-using-csom-and-pnp-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/export-lists-schema-to-xml-using-csom-and-pnp-comments/</guid>
      <description>Create Lists Libraries from Schema as XML using CSOM | reshmeeauckloo - Oct 6, 2016
[…] ← Export Lists Schema to XML using CSOM and PnP […]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export Lists Schema to XML using CSOM and PnP</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/export-lists-schema-to-xml-using-csom-and-pnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/export-lists-schema-to-xml-using-csom-and-pnp/</guid>
      <description>I had to automate deployment of lists and libraries into different environments, e.g. on premises and online. There are different elements to consider when deploying lists or libraries namely - List Properties - List Content Types - Views - Fields I could have written a configuration file in xml manually to specify the details above. Instead I have decided to configure lists and libraries from a SharePoint 2013 On Premises Dev environment and export the list schemaXML property to a XML file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Search Result Web Part: Query Text and Result Source</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/update-search-result-web-part-query-text-and-result-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 08:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/update-search-result-web-part-query-text-and-result-source/</guid>
      <description>I had to automate update of result source and query of a search result web part in a search page as part of deployment script to move changes from DEV to TEST, UAT and PROD. The XML definition of a search result web part is Cannot import this Web Part. 4 True advanced.aspx True False True True True null False True [&amp;quot;~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Group_Default.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Item_Default.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Item_Site.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Item_Word.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Item_PowerPoint.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Item_Person_CompactHorizontal.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Item_BestBet.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Item_WebPage.js&amp;quot;] 10 True True False True True Modeless Search Results True 1 True False ~sitecollection/_catalogs/masterpage/Display Templates/Search/Item_CommonItem_Body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Refiner to Refinement Web Part using CSOM and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/add-refiner-to-refinement-web-part-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 06:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/add-refiner-to-refinement-web-part-comments/</guid>
      <description>Update Search Result Web Part: Query Text and Result Source | reshmeeauckloo - Oct 6, 2016
[…] ← Add Refiner to Refinement Web Part using CSOM and PowerShell […]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Refiner to Refinement Web Part using CSOM and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/add-refiner-to-refinement-web-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 06:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/add-refiner-to-refinement-web-part/</guid>
      <description>The refinement web part present by default on a search results page help to narrow down search results. The inter connected web parts present in a search result page are
Search Box Web Part Search Navigation Search Results Refinement Web Part The refinement web part used refiners which are managed properties bound to crawled properties created by search crawl. The managed properties must be enabled as refiners to be able to use on the web part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create default groups using CSOM and PowerShell after creating site collections via script</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-default-groups-using-csom-and-powershell-after-creating-site-collections-via-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 16:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-default-groups-using-csom-and-powershell-after-creating-site-collections-via-script/</guid>
      <description>Whenever a site collection is created using PowerShell, the default security groups (visitors, owners and members) are not provisioned. When site collection is created via browser an additional method call is made to create the security groups which is not called while using PowerShell.
The following scripts will help create the default groups.
https://gist.github.com/reshmee011/7c4ac90cb3038d16fa1448f4c5678896 Call method CreateWebDefaultGroup passing the parameters context(clientcontext) and UniquePermissions(bool) CreateWebDefaultGroup -Context $ctx -UniquePermissions $false</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provision Search Navigation Settings PnP PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/provision-search-navigation-settings-pnp-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 16:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/provision-search-navigation-settings-pnp-powershell/</guid>
      <description>I was investigating ways how to provision a search centre site with all the configurations automatically. I tried to package all configurations from an already configured Search Centre using &amp;ldquo;Save site as template&amp;rdquo;, however it did not work as Publishing Features are activated in a Search Centre. There are different configuration elements in a search centre site
Search Navigation Settings Custom Search Display Templates Custom Search Results Pages which can be created using the function Add-PublishingPage Configure web parts in the search results page Refinement WebPart Search Results WebPart This blog post focuses on updating the Search Navigation Settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest Api Generate Guest Link SharePoint Online</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-anonymous-link-sharepoint-online-rest-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 17:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-anonymous-link-sharepoint-online-rest-comments/</guid>
      <description>vamsim - Jun 3, 2017
Hi this is very helpful, but can you help with the steps to execute this. Also a clear explanation of all the parameters used will really help a lot of people.
what is the adequate permission one needs on the resource to create its anonymous link, I have logged in as read only user and i am getting access denied error while executing above script, can you explain this</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest Api Generate Guest Link SharePoint Online</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-anonymous-link-sharepoint-online-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 17:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/create-anonymous-link-sharepoint-online-rest/</guid>
      <description>The CreateAnonymousLink method creates an anonymous link with option either to read or edit. It is quite useful to share documents with external users. The drawback is that anyone with the link can view/edit the document shared without sign-in. The method &amp;ldquo;CreateAnonymousLink &amp;quot; accomplishes the same as &amp;ldquo;View Link - no sign-in required&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Edit Link -no sign-in required&amp;rdquo; from the UI. https://gist.github.com/reshmee011/1f08ae19491e5c094986dfdb55f29731 Once the link is generated, it can be sent by email to the relevant individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export Term Set from Term Store as Sample Import file CSV</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/export-term-set-from-term-store-as-sample-import-file-csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 16:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/export-term-set-from-term-store-as-sample-import-file-csv/</guid>
      <description>The Managed Metadata service provides the &amp;ldquo;Import Term Set&amp;rdquo; Out of the Box. Unfortunately it does not provide the same &amp;ldquo;Export Term Set&amp;rdquo; capability. I had a requirement to export a term set to be reviewed by the business before importing the term set to another SharePoint farm. The Sample Import File has the columns &amp;ldquo;Term Set Name&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Term Set Description&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;LCID&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Available for Tagging&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Term Description&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Level 1 Term&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Level 2 Term&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Level 3 Term&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Level 4 Term&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Level 5 Term&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;Level 6 Term&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Level 7 Term&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Indexed(Queryable via Search) Web PropertyBag using PnP and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/set-a-propertybag-property-as-indexed-queryable-via-search-using-pnp-and-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 16:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/set-a-propertybag-property-as-indexed-queryable-via-search-using-pnp-and-powershell/</guid>
      <description>PropertyBag set against SharePoint web object can be indexed which means a corresponding crawled property is created by Search. If search managed properties are created against the crawled property (property bag values), custom search display templates can be created to provide a site directory solution. The post by Phil Harding Set a PropertyBag Property as Indexed (Queryable via Search) using CSOM + Powershell describes how to create an indexed property on premises using the collection &amp;ldquo;IndexedPropertyKeys&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply Theme and Create Composed Look CSOM and PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/apply-theme-and-create-composed-look-csom-and-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 16:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/apply-theme-and-create-composed-look-csom-and-powershell/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways a theme can be applied to a SharePoint site. I tried the PnP command SetSPOTheme as follows on SharePoint 2013 On Premises instance. Set-SPOTheme -ColorPaletteUrl $PathThemeColor -FontSchemeUrl $PathThemeFont Unfortunately I was getting message &amp;lsquo;Field or property &amp;ldquo;AlternateCssUrl&amp;rdquo; does not exist.&amp;rsquo; The error is due not having latest patch installed. Unfortunately the latest SharePoint CU can&amp;rsquo;t be installed as we have heavily customised legacy applications migrated from SharePoint 2007 and SharePoint 2010 running in compatibility mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metalogix Import From FileShare To SharePoint - Extract Folder Name from FilePath using CSOM PnP</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/metalogix-import-from-fileshare-to-sharepoint-extract-folder-name-from-filepath-using-csom-pnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 21:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/metalogix-import-from-fileshare-to-sharepoint-extract-folder-name-from-filepath-using-csom-pnp/</guid>
      <description>I was evaluating the Metalogix tool for Migration from fileshare to SharePoint. The file share edition needs to be selected while installing the Metalogix content matrix tool. The good news is that it can fulfil the following requirements:
Migrate files recursively from within folders , i.e. flatten folder Replace illegal characters with character specified Handle duplicate by either overwriting file or not moving file The CreatedBy, CreatedDate, ModifedBy and ModifiedDate file properties can be maintained by mapping these properties to SharePoint respective Out of the Box columns Can apply custom filter on the following Created Before Created After Modified Before Modified After File Size Max Can migrate user permission as set on the folder/file from fileShare to SharePoint, however I could not find option how to map to SharePoint Groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Choice Field values using CSOM in PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/update-choice-field-values-using-csom-in-powershell-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 16:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/update-choice-field-values-using-csom-in-powershell-comments/</guid>
      <description>Chris O&amp;rsquo;Connor - Oct 5, 2017
Thanks !! This was an awesome tip - and works in SharePoint Online. I have an &amp;ldquo;Events&amp;rdquo; list to clear out - and just add PUBLIC + PRIVATE. This technique worked great - thanks again. :-)
http://veerainduvasi.blogspot.co.uk/2017/01/update-exisiting-choice-column-options.html
Awesome! AND timely! Two questions: Will this work against a Sharepoint Online doc library with more than 5000 items? Can this alter an existing choice value as well as adding a new one?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Choice Field values using CSOM in PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/update-choice-field-values-using-csom-in-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 16:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/update-choice-field-values-using-csom-in-powershell/</guid>
      <description>I wanted a CSOM script in PowerShell to add a new value to a choice field in SharePoint. Most of the examples I found were in CSOM Managed Code (C#) but could not find anything in PowerShell. I came up with the embedded code. The client assemblies are referenced
SharePoint Assemblies\Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.dll SharePoint Assemblies\Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.Runtime.dll I have created the function Add-ChoiceValueToField to contain the logic to add a value to a choice field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import/Export Columns and Content Types using PnP PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/importexport-columns-and-content-types-sharepointpnp2016powershell-powershell-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 11:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/importexport-columns-and-content-types-sharepointpnp2016powershell-powershell-comments/</guid>
      <description>reshmee011 - Oct 4, 2017
I will update the scripts at some point. Thanks for the comment.
The Imported TaxonomyFields seems not working, because of missing the second Taxonomy-Note-Field. I always get &amp;ldquo;The SPListItem being updated was not retrieved with all taxonomy fields&amp;rdquo; in Edit-Form of the imported Managed Metadata Columns. I have observed this. http://blog.bugrapostaci.com/2015/07/03/the-splistitem-being-updated-was-not-retrieved-with-all-taxonomy-fields/
Actually you must use the new PnP-PowerShell-Namespace in the PowerShell-Commands. Example: Connect-PnPOnline instead of Connect-SPOnline and so on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import/Export Columns and Content Types using PnP PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/importexport-columns-and-content-types-sharepointpnp2016powershell-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 11:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/importexport-columns-and-content-types-sharepointpnp2016powershell-powershell/</guid>
      <description>It is useful to migrate Site Columns and Content Types from one Site Collection to another under the following scenarios maintaining the original GUIDS.
SharePoint On Premise environment to SharePoint Online Within SharePoint Online, migrate to another tenant If Content Hub Feature is not used, migrate the contents to another site collection Keep a list for governance/change tracking purpose, i.e. checking in TFS This article covers export/import of site columns and content types using SharePointPnP2016PowerShell commands which needs to be installed to be able to use the relevant commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSOM in PowerShell Query All Unique Permissions</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/csom-query-all-unique-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 20:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/csom-query-all-unique-permissions/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a script to export all unique permissions/broken permissions for sites, lists or document libraries and Pages items.From a quick Google search, I stumbled upon SharePoint 2010: Export All Unique Permissions from Site Collection using PowerShell. The script would have worked on SharePoint 2013 given it was run directly from the SharePoint server using Server Side Code. I was site collection administrator without access to any SharePoint Servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nintex SharePoint Online Create SharePoint Group with Contribute permissions</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/nintex-sharepoint-online-create-sharepoint-group-with-contribute-permissions-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 14:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/nintex-sharepoint-online-create-sharepoint-group-with-contribute-permissions-comments/</guid>
      <description>Mixons - Nov 1, 2016
@Dub do you found the solution ?? i have the same problem
Hello Reshmee, Great tutorial! I could confirm that the content type has to be text/xml (as described above). But when I try to create the Group. I got the following error message: &amp;ldquo;Access denied. You do not have permission to perform this action or access this resource&amp;rdquo;
Hi, has anyone found a solution to this Access denied error?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nintex SharePoint Online Create SharePoint Group with Contribute permissions</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/nintex-sharepoint-online-create-sharepoint-group-with-contribute-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 14:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/nintex-sharepoint-online-create-sharepoint-group-with-contribute-permissions/</guid>
      <description>Nintex Workflow has actions &amp;ldquo;Web Request&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Call HTTP Web Service&amp;rdquo; which can be used to make calls to the REST API of SharePoint Online/2013 to automate creation of SharePoint groups in a site collection. Add the following steps to the workflow
Create a Text variable GroupName and Use &amp;ldquo;Set Workflow Variable&amp;rdquo; to assign it to a value. Get request digest from targeted site collection. Please note that workflow app permissions need to amended to give site collection full control access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSOM SharePoint Online Create Term with custom shared and local properties</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/jsom-sharepoint-online-create-term-with-custom-shared-and-local-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 21:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/jsom-sharepoint-online-create-term-with-custom-shared-and-local-properties/</guid>
      <description>The sp.Taxonomy.js can be used to create a term in the taxonomy store. I wanted to create Shared Custom properties on the term. However the JavaScript library on MSDN mentions only the method setLocalCustomProperty which creates or updates a local custom property. The SetCustomProperty is mentioned in MSDN to use in CSOM managed code to create or update shared custom property on a term. There is a lack of documentation how to use the method in JSOM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint JSOM to update Document ID Settings</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-jsom-to-update-document-id-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 05:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-jsom-to-update-document-id-settings/</guid>
      <description>The Document ID Service feature is useful to tag unique Id to documents across site collection to make it easier to retrieve. A prefix can be specified to use when the unique Id is generated. The document id settings is stored in the web property bag &amp;ldquo;docid_settings_ui&amp;rdquo; after the feature the activated. The web property bag can be updated using JSOM to assign a prefix with XML snippet like below. var docIdValue = &amp;lsquo; &amp;rsquo; + docIDPrefix + &amp;lsquo; true&amp;rsquo; webProperties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell break inheritance on SharePoint Library and change permissions of Group</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/powershell-break-inheritance-on-sharepoint-library-and-change-permissions-of-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 08:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/powershell-break-inheritance-on-sharepoint-library-and-change-permissions-of-group/</guid>
      <description>I had a requirement to change group members security group which has contribute permissions at the site collection to have read permissions to one document library. The trick is to break inheritance on the document library and amend the role of the security group to Read. $web =Get-SPWeb -Identity $webUrl $docLibrary=$web.Lists.TryGetList($LibraryName) $docLibrary.BreakRoleInheritance($False) #get role definition from web: Full Control or Contribute or Read $roleDefinitions = &amp;quot;Read&amp;quot; #get site group $siteGroup = $web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Display Template js file not created when HTML file for Item_ThreeLines is created</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/search-display-template-js-file-not-created-when-html-file-for-item_threelines-is-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 23:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/search-display-template-js-file-not-created-when-html-file-for-item_threelines-is-created/</guid>
      <description>On a SharePoint Online site collection where Publishing feature was initially turned on and subsequently turned off, js file was not automatically created/updated whenever a display template was created/edited. We wanted to have a search content web part with three lines instead of two lines. We created a new display template by following the steps below.
Navigate to Site Settings&amp;gt;Master Pages&amp;gt;Display Templates&amp;gt;Content Web Parts. Download the file Item_TwoLines.html Rename it to Item_ThreeLines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint 2013: How to increase the file upload limit for CSOM from 2 Mb to 20 Mb</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-2013-how-to-increase-the-file-upload-limit-for-csom-from-2-mb-to-20-mb-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 21:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-2013-how-to-increase-the-file-upload-limit-for-csom-from-2-mb-to-20-mb-comments/</guid>
      <description>FLEURY Romain (@radjkill) - Mar 2, 2016
Great !!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint 2013: How to increase the file upload limit for CSOM from 2 Mb to 20 Mb</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-2013-how-to-increase-the-file-upload-limit-for-csom-from-2-mb-to-20-mb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 21:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-2013-how-to-increase-the-file-upload-limit-for-csom-from-2-mb-to-20-mb/</guid>
      <description>In SharePoint 2013, the default file size limit set in Central Administration is for uploading single file manually in SharePoint libraries or using server side code. When I was trying to upload a file more than 2 MB using CSOM, the following error was thrown The request message is too large. The server does not allow messages that are larger than 2097152 bytes. I tried the fix mentioned in the post http://sharepoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS to update display of items in SharePoint List View with alternating colour</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/css-to-update-display-of-items-in-sharepoint-list-view-with-alternating-colour-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 22:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/css-to-update-display-of-items-in-sharepoint-list-view-with-alternating-colour-comments/</guid>
      <description>Will - Dec 4, 2021
How would you set the background for a specific row using the css?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS to update display of items in SharePoint List View with alternating colour</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/css-to-update-display-of-items-in-sharepoint-list-view-with-alternating-colour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 22:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/css-to-update-display-of-items-in-sharepoint-list-view-with-alternating-colour/</guid>
      <description>The list view display of items in a SharePoint List can be updated to have alternating row colour and border set by using CSS. To test the snippet below, edit the page displaying the list items and add a content editor WebPart. Copy and paste the CSS snippet into the content editor WebPart. /*&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-*/ /* &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Set Alternating Rows &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- */ /* &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Set background for every row &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- */ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Server 2013/Online - Customise Track your work WebPart tile colour using CSS</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/project-server-2013-customise-track-your-work-webpart-tile-colour-using-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 19:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/project-server-2013-customise-track-your-work-webpart-tile-colour-using-css/</guid>
      <description>In Project Server 2013/Online, there is Track Your Work WebPart which can be added to a page. The composed look can be updated to change the colour of the tiles. If each tile needs a different colour, custom css needs to be used. Copy and paste the css code below into a content editor WebPart. /* &amp;mdash;- #64D9E9 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Light Blue /* &amp;mdash;- #FFDE7B &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Yellow /* &amp;mdash;- #D467A3 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Pink /* &amp;mdash;- #FF6685 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Red /*&amp;mdash;- #FF0033 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Carmine red /* &amp;mdash;- #A995C1 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Purple /* &amp;mdash;- #97D4A3 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Green /* &amp;mdash;- #667F97 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Dark Blue /*&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-*/ /*&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-*/ /* &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; Change the color of the tiles &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; Adding more colors change the 7n to 8n, etc to continue adding colors */ div.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS SharePoint Integrated Mode - Cells grow vertically to fit content</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode-cells-grow-vertically-to-fit-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 17:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode-cells-grow-vertically-to-fit-content/</guid>
      <description>I have come across this issue several times that even the &amp;ldquo;Can Grow&amp;rdquo; property of the cell is set to false, the cell grows vertically to fit contents forcing the same row to stretch to the height of the cell distorting the rendering of the report on the browser though it might display correctly in Report Builder or SQL data tools in Visual Studio. Can Grow is set to False from the cell property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Script to Remove Theme from Sub Sites</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/powershell-script-to-remove-theme-from-sub-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 16:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/powershell-script-to-remove-theme-from-sub-sites/</guid>
      <description>I had a requirement to apply a custom css file to a SharePoint collection on which there was a custom composed look with background image applied. I used the composed look option to reset the theme to a default without background image on the main site collection URL. Unfortunately sub sites were still displaying the background image. I tried setting the theme of the Sub Site using function ApplyTo or ApplyTheme without luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building SSRS using Report Builder for Project Server On Premises</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/building-ssrs-using-report-builder-for-project-server-on-premises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/building-ssrs-using-report-builder-for-project-server-on-premises/</guid>
      <description>1. Article Purpose I have worked with SSRS for nearly five years now. It is an efficient tool to display data from Project Server Reporting database. This article provides a step to step guide how to create reports using Report Builder from Project Server 2010 /2013 (On Premises) environment.
2. Report Builder Report Builder is a report authoring tool that helps to design, test, print and manage reports. Different type of reports can be created using a combination of tables, matrices, lists, and charts depending on reporting needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insert link to CSS/JavaScript script from &#34;Site Assets&#34; library using custom action SharePoint</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/insert-link-to-cssjavascript-script-from-site-assets-library-using-custom-action-sharepoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 23:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/insert-link-to-cssjavascript-script-from-site-assets-library-using-custom-action-sharepoint/</guid>
      <description>I had a requirement from a client to apply custom css and JavaScript to a site collection including sub sites. The JavaScript file and Css file can be uploaded to &amp;ldquo;Site Assets&amp;rdquo; library using Module Element in SharePoint solution Module element to deploy CSS file &amp;lt;Elements xmlns=&amp;ldquo;http://schemas.microsoft.com/sharepoint/&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Module Name=&amp;ldquo;CustomCss&amp;rdquo; Url=&amp;ldquo;SiteAssets&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;File Path=&amp;ldquo;CustomCss\custom.css&amp;rdquo; Url=&amp;ldquo;CustomCss\custom.css&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Module&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Elements&amp;gt; Module element to deploy CSS file &amp;lt;Elements xmlns=&amp;ldquo;http://schemas.microsoft.com/sharepoint/&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Module Name=&amp;ldquo;Jquery&amp;rdquo; Url=&amp;ldquo;SiteAssets&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;File Path=&amp;ldquo;Jquery\jquery-1.11.1.min.js&amp;rdquo; Url=&amp;ldquo;Jquery/jquery-1.11.1.min.js&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Module&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Elements&amp;gt; There are two options how to add the reference o the js file and css file</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Server 2013 Make fields Read Only in PDP depending on SharePoint Groups the logged user belong to</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/project-server-2013-make-fields-read-only-in-pdp-depending-on-sharepoint-groups-the-logged-user-belong-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 17:04:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/project-server-2013-make-fields-read-only-in-pdp-depending-on-sharepoint-groups-the-logged-user-belong-to/</guid>
      <description>I had a requirement depending on the SharePoint group the user belong some fields need to be read only. The script below disable the field &amp;ldquo;Project Code&amp;rdquo; on the PDP (Project Detail Page) if the user is not in the SharePoint group &amp;ldquo;Project Code&amp;rdquo;. Copy the code snippet to a script editor web part in a PDP page. jQuery.noConflict(); function IsCurrentUserMemberOfGroup(groupName, OnComplete) { var currentContext = new SP.ClientContext.get_current(); var currentWeb = currentContext.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate SharePoint Workflow 2013 as visio file</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/migrate-reusable-sharepoint-workflow-2013-as-visio-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 16:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/migrate-reusable-sharepoint-workflow-2013-as-visio-file/</guid>
      <description>I had to migrate a SharePoint Designer 2013 workflow to an environment. The workflow was exported to visio as a .vwi file. Unfortunately when the I tried to import the file using the &amp;ldquo;Import as visio&amp;rdquo; option from SharePoint Designer, the message was appearing &amp;ldquo;This workflow cannot be imported because it was created in SharePoint Designer for a different site, or the original workflow has been moved or deleted.&amp;rdquo; I stumbled upon the blog below how to fix the migration issue https://aniketahmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS Subscription SharePoint Integrated Mode</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-subscription-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 16:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ssrs-subscription-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</guid>
      <description>Subscription option is available on the SSRS report item to allow the run the report automatically. The user need to be logged in as site administrator to create subscription. Follow the steps below
Create a document library (named for example “Extracts” to store the report extracts. Click on “Manage Subscriptions” from the drop down options available against the SSRS report item. Click on “Add Subscription”. Update the fields Delivery Extension = SharePoint Document Library Document Library = The document library created in first step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Date Parameterer to en-GB SSRS 2012 SharePoint Integrated mode</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/changing-date-parameterer-to-en-gb-ssrs-2012-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 16:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/changing-date-parameterer-to-en-gb-ssrs-2012-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</guid>
      <description>I have seen the issues several times where date/time parameters used to filter date in SSRS reports are switched to en-US despite the language of the reports is set to en-GB. If dates like 24/12/2015 or 15/12/2015 are picked , the report fails to load due to invalid date format. I came across the article that describes a fix. http://www.tachytelic.net/2013/01/changing-the-format-of-date-parameters-on-a-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-report-that-is-sharepoint-integrated/ Hard code the UICulture value in RSViewerPage.aspx, found in C:\Program Files\Common Files\Microsoft Shared\Web Server Extensions\15\TEMPLATE\LAYOUTS\ReportServer The modified code will look like: &amp;lt;%@ Page language=&amp;ldquo;C#&amp;rdquo; Codebehind=&amp;ldquo;RSViewerPage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint JavaScript OOB Utilities URL</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-javascript-oob-utilities-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 22:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-javascript-oob-utilities-url/</guid>
      <description>SharePoint provides Out of Box JavaScript libraries to manipulate URL property. GetUrlKeyValue(KeyName, bNoDecode, url, bCaseInsensitive) Gets the key value from url. The second parameter is a Booleans indicating whether the value needs decoding and the last parameter indicates whether key is case sensitive SetUrlKeyValue(keyName, keyValue, bEncode, url) Set the value of key in the Url. The third parameter indicates whether the value needs to be encoded The two functions below are useful before saving a file to detect any illegal characters in url and file name as both have different sets of illegal characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint, Approve Selected List Items</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-approve-selected-list-items-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 18:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-approve-selected-list-items-comments/</guid>
      <description>Lilia Georgieva - Aug 4, 2016
Hi there, can you provide some advice here. When I copy-paste your code in the Script Editor, I don&amp;rsquo;t get buttons but Text fields instead. The javascript code also doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me. Any troubleshooting ideas?
Hi Lilia Thanks very much for trying my code. The single and double quotes got messed up. I have replaced the code with a link to github https://gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint, Approve Selected List Items</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-approve-selected-list-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 18:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-approve-selected-list-items/</guid>
      <description>SharePoint provides Out of the box JavaScript Libraries. The List Views functions are described in the post with an example how to apply some of the functions CountSelectedItems(ctx); return count of selected items in view SelectRowByIndex(ctx,1,true); selects first item in list view DeselectAllItems(ctx, tab.rows, false);deselects all items in view SelectRibbonTab(&amp;ldquo;Ribbon.ListItem&amp;rdquo;,true); displays the listitem ribbon The code below can be copied into a script editor web part on a list view page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint REST Get all items __next</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-rest-get-all-items-__next/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-rest-get-all-items-__next/</guid>
      <description>When a REST query is run against a SharePoint list, not all items are returned if it contains more than 100 items. The default server paging is 100. It is a good practice to check the __next property of the JSON results to make sure all items are returned. Below is a code snippet running from a SharePoint hosted add-in. var url = appUrl + &amp;quot;/_api/SP.AppContextSite(@target)/Web/Lists/getByTitle(&#39;Repairs&#39;)/Items?$select=Title&amp;amp;@target=&#39;&amp;quot; + hostUrl + &amp;quot;&#39;&amp;quot;; jQuery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint 2013/Online CSOM REST Web Proxy</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-2013-csom-rest-web-proxy-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-2013-csom-rest-web-proxy-comments/</guid>
      <description>parthrawal - Jun 5, 2016
can you please share the code for POST method!? i have currently JS in content editor webpart and want to use the same. can i!?
Could you please share code snippet for post data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint 2013/Online CSOM REST Web Proxy</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-2013-csom-rest-web-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-2013-csom-rest-web-proxy/</guid>
      <description>Web Proxy SP.WebProxy is used to make requests to external services by SharePoint. SharePoint Add-ins must register target site as remote endpoint in app manifest. If the URL is http://services.odata.org/v4/Northwind/Northwind.svc/Categories?$format=json, the endpoint is http://services.odata.org. However the response size must not exceed 200 kb. CSOM var context = SP.ClientContext.get_current(); var request = new SP.WebRequestInfo(); request.set_url(&amp;quot;http://services.odata.org/v4/Northwind/Northwind.svc/Categories?$format=json&amp;quot;); request.set_method(&amp;quot;GET&amp;quot;); var response = SP.WebProxy.invoke(context,request); context.executeQueryAsync(success, fail); function success(){ if(response.get_statusCode() == 200 { var data = JSON.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing Date Parameter To SubReport SSRS SharePoint Integrated Mode</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/passing-date-parameter-to-subreport-ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 18:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/passing-date-parameter-to-subreport-ssrs-sharepoint-integrated-mode/</guid>
      <description>When SSRS is rendered in SharePoint Integrated Mode if there is a drop down parameter of type DateTime and it is passed to a parameter of DateTime in the SubReport, the subreport fails to load when rendering in browser though it loads correctly from reportbuilder. Again much pain, I decided to convert the date parameters into Text as the parameters were drop down displaying in dd/MM/yyyy format. The SQL query to populate the parameter SELECT CONVERT(nvarchar(10),Min(TimeByDay),103) DisplayDate ,Convert(date,Min(TimeByDay)) StartTime ,CONVERT(VARCHAR(10), Min(TimeByDay), 112) FormatStartTime FROM [dbo].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ustom Layout Results Page to allow sorting and filtering by property</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ustom-layout-results-page-to-allow-sorting-and-filtering-by-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 00:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/ustom-layout-results-page-to-allow-sorting-and-filtering-by-property/</guid>
      <description>Content query webpart does not give the same flexibility as search results page to allow user to filter and sort by property. SharePoint Online provides out of the box display template which can be used in results page. However if custom property needs to be displayed or a custom display format is needed , then a new search result page can be created. Assuming news items need to be displayed in the following format with filters Country and Subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert UTC Date returned from SharePoint API to Local time using JavaScript and C#</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/convert-utc-date-returned-from-sharepoint-api-to-local-time-using-javascript-and-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 12:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/convert-utc-date-returned-from-sharepoint-api-to-local-time-using-javascript-and-c/</guid>
      <description>SharePoint Online stores all date fields in UTC format and convert it to appropriate time zone whenever it is retrieved by a user. However when using SharePoint API, the date returned is in UTC format and have to be converted to local time. Using the JavaScript function below the local time can be returned. self.toLocalDate = function (utc_date) { //The getTimezoneOffset() value is in minutes var offset = new Date().getTimezoneOffset(); //offset will be in minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Resources Custom Field values using CSOM, Project Online, #Project Server 2013</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/updating-resources-custom-field-values-using-csom-project-online-project-server-2013-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 18:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/updating-resources-custom-field-values-using-csom-project-online-project-server-2013-comments/</guid>
      <description>anil - May 5, 2016
You can update custom field using csom. Follow the link below http://projectservercode.com/tag/how-to-update-custom-field-using-csom/
Hi Anil. i am getting below error, can you please suggest me if there are any other way to fix it. projContext.ExecuteQuery(); An unhandled exception of type &amp;lsquo;Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.ServerException&amp;rsquo; occurred in Microsoft.SharePoint.Client.Runtime.dll Additional information: PJClientCallableException: CustomFieldRequiredValueNotProvided Below is my code. static string UserName = &amp;ldquo;raghava@hosting.com&amp;rdquo;; static string Passwords = &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo;; static void Main(string[] args) { string pwaPath = &amp;ldquo;https://epmsolutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Resources Custom Field values using CSOM, Project Online, #Project Server 2013</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/updating-resources-custom-field-values-using-csom-project-online-project-server-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 18:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/updating-resources-custom-field-values-using-csom-project-online-project-server-2013/</guid>
      <description>Project Online applications need to be written using CSOM or OData rather the PSI which will be deprecated soon. The CSOM - Client-side object model implements common server functionality. If you are not familiar with development in Project Server 2013 refer to the links below to learn about CSOM, OData, JSOM. ProjectData - Project 2013 OData service reference https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/office/jj163015(v=office.15).aspx Client-side object model (CSOM) for Project 2013 https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/office/jj163123(v=office.15).aspx What the CSOM does and does not do https://msdn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update User Profile Property using Web Service Request action in Nintex</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/update-user-profile-property-using-web-service-request-action-in-nintex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 17:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/update-user-profile-property-using-web-service-request-action-in-nintex/</guid>
      <description>In SharePoint Online, Nintex workflow can be used to update a user profile property. Before using Nintex Workflow to update user it needs to be given the right permissions
Allow workflow to use app permissions a. Navigate to site settings
b. Under Site Actions, click Manage site features
c. Locate the Workflows can app permissions and click Activate if it is not activated yet.
2. Allow workflow to use app permissions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST or CSOM with JavaScript to find if user is in particular SharePoint group</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/rest-or-csom-with-javascript-to-find-if-user-is-in-particular-sharepoint-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 15:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/rest-or-csom-with-javascript-to-find-if-user-is-in-particular-sharepoint-group/</guid>
      <description>Initially I used REST call to find out whether the user is in a particular SharePoint group in SharePoint 2013. Though it works fine when the logged in user is an administrator or part of the queried group, the rest call to /_api/web/sitegroups/getbyid(xx)/users keeps prompting for user name and password for non-administrator users throwing access denied exception at the end. After a while investigating, I could not find anything to resolve the rest call issue and I decided to find to alternatives way to find out if the user is in a particular group.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
