<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JavaScript on m365 blog</title>
    <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JavaScript on m365 blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 16:23:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting taxonomy field into cascading drop down fields using PnP Branding.JsLink</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/converting-taxonomy-field-into-cascading-drop-down-fields-using-pnp-branding-jslink-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 16:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/converting-taxonomy-field-into-cascading-drop-down-fields-using-pnp-branding-jslink-comments/</guid>
      <description>Arul Britto Kumar - Nov 4, 2017
Hi Mr.Jozsef, Is it possible use multiple manage metadata fileds? because I have 3 manage metadata columns
Hi reshmee Is it possible to see how you have created the list Is documnettype a list I can’t seem to get it working</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting taxonomy field into cascading drop down fields using PnP Branding.JsLink</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/converting-taxonomy-field-into-cascading-drop-down-fields-using-pnp-branding-jslink/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 16:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/converting-taxonomy-field-into-cascading-drop-down-fields-using-pnp-branding-jslink/</guid>
      <description>Managed metadata fields don&amp;rsquo;t provide the same look and feel as choice field type. It is quick clunky specially when there are a lot of terms displayed. The requirement cropped up to display the managed metadata fields as drop downs. After googling for a while, stumbled on PnP sample Branding.JSLink solution which had an example how to achieve it. The solution is a no code sandboxed solution with different examples how to enrich fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filter N-N Add existing Look Up Contact Custom View CRM 2015</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/filter-n-n-add-existing-look-up-contact-custom-view-crm-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 10:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/filter-n-n-add-existing-look-up-contact-custom-view-crm-2015/</guid>
      <description>I had a requirement to add contacts where the [Account Type] is &amp;ldquo;Lawyer&amp;rdquo; to entity &amp;ldquo;Case&amp;rdquo;. I created a relationship N:N between contacts and cases. Unfortunately the filter for N-N Add Existing button on a sub grid stopped working on from version CRM 2013. It does not work on CRM 2015 on Premises as well. I stumbled upon the blog Filter N:N Add Existing Lookup Dynamics CRM 2013 how to resolve the issue using the CRM function** LookupObjectsWithCallback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSOM SharePoint Online Create Term with custom shared and local properties</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/jsom-sharepoint-online-create-term-with-custom-shared-and-local-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 21:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/jsom-sharepoint-online-create-term-with-custom-shared-and-local-properties/</guid>
      <description>The sp.Taxonomy.js can be used to create a term in the taxonomy store. I wanted to create Shared Custom properties on the term. However the JavaScript library on MSDN mentions only the method setLocalCustomProperty which creates or updates a local custom property. The SetCustomProperty is mentioned in MSDN to use in CSOM managed code to create or update shared custom property on a term. There is a lack of documentation how to use the method in JSOM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint JSOM to update Document ID Settings</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-jsom-to-update-document-id-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 05:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-jsom-to-update-document-id-settings/</guid>
      <description>The Document ID Service feature is useful to tag unique Id to documents across site collection to make it easier to retrieve. A prefix can be specified to use when the unique Id is generated. The document id settings is stored in the web property bag &amp;ldquo;docid_settings_ui&amp;rdquo; after the feature the activated. The web property bag can be updated using JSOM to assign a prefix with XML snippet like below. var docIdValue = &amp;lsquo; &amp;rsquo; + docIDPrefix + &amp;lsquo; true&amp;rsquo; webProperties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Display Template js file not created when HTML file for Item_ThreeLines is created</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/search-display-template-js-file-not-created-when-html-file-for-item_threelines-is-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 23:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/search-display-template-js-file-not-created-when-html-file-for-item_threelines-is-created/</guid>
      <description>On a SharePoint Online site collection where Publishing feature was initially turned on and subsequently turned off, js file was not automatically created/updated whenever a display template was created/edited. We wanted to have a search content web part with three lines instead of two lines. We created a new display template by following the steps below.
Navigate to Site Settings&amp;gt;Master Pages&amp;gt;Display Templates&amp;gt;Content Web Parts. Download the file Item_TwoLines.html Rename it to Item_ThreeLines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insert link to CSS/JavaScript script from &#34;Site Assets&#34; library using custom action SharePoint</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/insert-link-to-cssjavascript-script-from-site-assets-library-using-custom-action-sharepoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 23:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/insert-link-to-cssjavascript-script-from-site-assets-library-using-custom-action-sharepoint/</guid>
      <description>I had a requirement from a client to apply custom css and JavaScript to a site collection including sub sites. The JavaScript file and Css file can be uploaded to &amp;ldquo;Site Assets&amp;rdquo; library using Module Element in SharePoint solution Module element to deploy CSS file &amp;lt;Elements xmlns=&amp;ldquo;http://schemas.microsoft.com/sharepoint/&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Module Name=&amp;ldquo;CustomCss&amp;rdquo; Url=&amp;ldquo;SiteAssets&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;File Path=&amp;ldquo;CustomCss\custom.css&amp;rdquo; Url=&amp;ldquo;CustomCss\custom.css&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Module&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Elements&amp;gt; Module element to deploy CSS file &amp;lt;Elements xmlns=&amp;ldquo;http://schemas.microsoft.com/sharepoint/&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Module Name=&amp;ldquo;Jquery&amp;rdquo; Url=&amp;ldquo;SiteAssets&amp;rdquo;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;File Path=&amp;ldquo;Jquery\jquery-1.11.1.min.js&amp;rdquo; Url=&amp;ldquo;Jquery/jquery-1.11.1.min.js&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Module&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/Elements&amp;gt; There are two options how to add the reference o the js file and css file</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Server 2013 Make fields Read Only in PDP depending on SharePoint Groups the logged user belong to</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/project-server-2013-make-fields-read-only-in-pdp-depending-on-sharepoint-groups-the-logged-user-belong-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 17:04:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/project-server-2013-make-fields-read-only-in-pdp-depending-on-sharepoint-groups-the-logged-user-belong-to/</guid>
      <description>I had a requirement depending on the SharePoint group the user belong some fields need to be read only. The script below disable the field &amp;ldquo;Project Code&amp;rdquo; on the PDP (Project Detail Page) if the user is not in the SharePoint group &amp;ldquo;Project Code&amp;rdquo;. Copy the code snippet to a script editor web part in a PDP page. jQuery.noConflict(); function IsCurrentUserMemberOfGroup(groupName, OnComplete) { var currentContext = new SP.ClientContext.get_current(); var currentWeb = currentContext.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting with React- Factorial react Component</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/starting-with-react-factorial-react-component/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 21:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/starting-with-react-factorial-react-component/</guid>
      <description>React is an Open Source, client-side web library for building composable user interfaces developed by Facebook and Instagram. The Instagram website, Facebook&amp;rsquo;s comment and like components are developed with React. React home page provides code samples that run live and give results just next to it. The getting started page provides necessary documentation and has a download link for the Starter Kit that&amp;rsquo;s a convenient package that includes HTML templates, the React libraries and this set of examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint JavaScript OOB Utilities URL</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-javascript-oob-utilities-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 22:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-javascript-oob-utilities-url/</guid>
      <description>SharePoint provides Out of Box JavaScript libraries to manipulate URL property. GetUrlKeyValue(KeyName, bNoDecode, url, bCaseInsensitive) Gets the key value from url. The second parameter is a Booleans indicating whether the value needs decoding and the last parameter indicates whether key is case sensitive SetUrlKeyValue(keyName, keyValue, bEncode, url) Set the value of key in the Url. The third parameter indicates whether the value needs to be encoded The two functions below are useful before saving a file to detect any illegal characters in url and file name as both have different sets of illegal characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint, Approve Selected List Items</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-approve-selected-list-items-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 18:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-approve-selected-list-items-comments/</guid>
      <description>Lilia Georgieva - Aug 4, 2016
Hi there, can you provide some advice here. When I copy-paste your code in the Script Editor, I don&amp;rsquo;t get buttons but Text fields instead. The javascript code also doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me. Any troubleshooting ideas?
Hi Lilia Thanks very much for trying my code. The single and double quotes got messed up. I have replaced the code with a link to github https://gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint, Approve Selected List Items</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-approve-selected-list-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 18:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-approve-selected-list-items/</guid>
      <description>SharePoint provides Out of the box JavaScript Libraries. The List Views functions are described in the post with an example how to apply some of the functions CountSelectedItems(ctx); return count of selected items in view SelectRowByIndex(ctx,1,true); selects first item in list view DeselectAllItems(ctx, tab.rows, false);deselects all items in view SelectRibbonTab(&amp;ldquo;Ribbon.ListItem&amp;rdquo;,true); displays the listitem ribbon The code below can be copied into a script editor web part on a list view page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Get list items and Effective Permissions on a list via REST API from SharePoint Add-in</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-get-list-items-and-effective-permissions-on-a-list-via-rest-api-from-sharepoint-add-in-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 09:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-get-list-items-and-effective-permissions-on-a-list-via-rest-api-from-sharepoint-add-in-comments/</guid>
      <description>Ofer Gal - Mar 3, 2017
I get error: Uncaught (in promise) TypeError: SP.BasePermissions is not a constructor What else should I load?
Sp.js needs to be loaded. Add the following to your page. /_layouts/15/sp.runtime.js /_layouts/15/sp.js</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Get list items and Effective Permissions on a list via REST API from SharePoint Add-in</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-get-list-items-and-effective-permissions-on-a-list-via-rest-api-from-sharepoint-add-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 09:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/sharepoint-get-list-items-and-effective-permissions-on-a-list-via-rest-api-from-sharepoint-add-in/</guid>
      <description>The requirement was to build a SharePoint hosted Add-in to allow logged user to create/edit list item from any site from the site collection. The permissions of the user to be able to create/edit an item against the list needed to be checked. The following script gets list items with effective permissions against the list using jQuery promises from the SharePoint hosted Add-in function getListItemsAndPermissions(webUrl, listTitle) { var appWebUrl = decodeURIComponent(getQueryStringParameter(&amp;quot;SPAppWebUrl&amp;quot;)); var deferredPermissions = $.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Switch Block - Break, Default, Fail-Through Allows Hierarchical code execution</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/the-switch-block-break-default-fail-through-allows-hierarchical-code-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 07:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/the-switch-block-break-default-fail-through-allows-hierarchical-code-execution/</guid>
      <description>The Switch Block allows to execute some code based on the value itself without a boolean check. Consider the block of code below function colour (id) { switch(id){ case 1: this.colour = &amp;quot;red&amp;quot;; case 2: this.colour = &amp;quot;blue&amp;quot;; case 3: this.colour = &amp;quot;yellow&amp;quot;; case 4: this.colour = &amp;quot;green&amp;quot;; } } var col = new colour(2); console.log(col.colour); The result of the above code is &amp;ldquo;green&amp;rdquo;. The case keyword and its value is just a label for an executable &amp;ldquo;starting point&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST or CSOM with JavaScript to find if user is in particular SharePoint group</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/rest-or-csom-with-javascript-to-find-if-user-is-in-particular-sharepoint-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 15:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/rest-or-csom-with-javascript-to-find-if-user-is-in-particular-sharepoint-group/</guid>
      <description>Initially I used REST call to find out whether the user is in a particular SharePoint group in SharePoint 2013. Though it works fine when the logged in user is an administrator or part of the queried group, the rest call to /_api/web/sitegroups/getbyid(xx)/users keeps prompting for user name and password for non-administrator users throwing access denied exception at the end. After a while investigating, I could not find anything to resolve the rest call issue and I decided to find to alternatives way to find out if the user is in a particular group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchange ActiveSync</title>
      <link>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/exchange-activesync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 15:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://famous-cajeta-4dad83.netlify.app/exchange-activesync/</guid>
      <description>Exchange ActiveSync devices can be configures to allow users to work in remote locations with high-latency or low-bandwidth networks. It allows users to access and reply to email messages and access calendars even when they are offline. Below is a link to Exchange ActiveSync http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa998357(v=exchg.150).aspx</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
